Carl Sachs

Detroit Metropolitan Area



sachscarl@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/carl-sachs

Summary

In December of 2019, I decided to jump into the growing tech industry, and joined Lambda School for Full-Stack Web Development.

I am a motivated and hard-working individual with a knack for juggling projects in a timely and efficient manner. I pick up on concepts quickly, and love to expand my knowledge learning by experience.

I am open to both remote and in-house opportunities, and would love to focus in React.js.

Experience



Lamda X

Lambda School

Sep 2020 - Present (1 month +)

I am currently looking for opportunities and working with Lambda X.

Student

Lambda School

Dec 2019 - Present (10 months +)

I studied Full-Stack Web Development at Lambda School. This included (but is not limited to): React.js, Node.js, HTML, CSS, Javascript, Python, Knex.js. I completed studies September 1, 2020.

Founder

InstantStrip

Feb 2018 - Dec 2019 (1 year 11 months)

InstantStrip was a company I founded in 2018 focused on fighting the Fentanyl epidemic. The idea was simple. Drug addicts won't stop doing drugs, so help them test their substances before use, as a small amount of Fentanyl can be fatal. I sold strips, tested most effective in the market by Johns Hopkins, that detected the presence of Fentanyl to a small dosage. I stopped running the business due to pending FDA approval and legal liabilities.

■ Bartender/Server

Andiamo Detroit Riverfront

Jan 2018 - Jun 2019 (1 year 6 months)

At Andiamo, not only did I spend my time creating and experimenting with exotic liquors to make a drink the customer wouldn't forget, but I learned how to interact with all types of people. The Renaissance Center located downtown Detroit, MI was home to a Marriott hotel frequently used by all types of business clientele.



Coach Insignia

Dec 2016 - May 2017 (6 months)

At Coach, we created the word professional. Everything we did had to be perfect. We once spent 3 hours setting and resetting a single table for when Mercedes hosted their Around-the-World party. My main takeaway was that the small details are what matter most.

Education



Lambda School

Endorsement, Full-Stack Web Development

2019 - 2020

I took Lambda's Full-Stack Web Development course, completed on September 1st, 2020. I am now looking for opportunities in the Lambda X program.

Wayne State University

Business Finance

2017 - 2019

I pursued an Entrepreneurship degree at Wayne State University.

Skills

Full-Stack Development • React.js • Software Development • Web Development • Node.js • Cascading Style Sheets (CSS) • HTML5 • Python • Bootstrap • React Native